Carlos Pambo

Engineering Lead at GGI Inc.

♥ Montréal, QC, Canada

 \Box +1 (514) 891-5177

✓ carlos.pambo@hotmail.com

♥ GitHub | In LinkedIn

Вю

Engineering lead, solutions architect and senior software engineer with over 8 years of experience. Skilled in agile software development methodologies, data science, machine learning, solutions and software components architecture, databases, backend services and integration development of web services, micro-services, data pipelines and operationalisation of machine learning models in public (AWS) and private cloud platforms.

Possesses technical and leadership skills demonstrated across multiple industries, including banking, financial and related services, telecommunications, logistics, media and advertisement, travel and tourism, and automotive.

PhD (Computer Engineering) candidate at Polytechnique Montréal (School of Engineering of the Université de Montréal). Studying under the supervision of Dr. Bentley Oakes, with research focused on the use of machine learning and low-code approaches to accelerate the construction of digital twins (DTs) for complex cyber-physical systems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CGI Inc. (CA)

Engineering Lead

June 2023 to Present

Engineering lead at CGI Inc.'s telecommunications business unit. Consults at Bell Canada on content discovery and data ingestion pipeline solutions. Responsible for identifying requirements, developing design structures, and coordinating with the product owners to review timelines and technical deliverables. He analyses ongoing projects and writes progress reports for all the involved stakeholders. Leads a team of 10 that includes software engineers, business analysis and QA engineers. Oversees their performance in the projects. Conducts security and performance audits and system modifications with the development team, product owners and senior managers.

BMW Group (ZA)

Solutions Architect Aug. 2022 to May 2023

Solutions architect at BMW Group's financial services business unit for the DCS and trade-in products to be used in BMW Group's future online sales model program.

Senior Software Engineer

Jun. 2021 to Jul. 2022

Senior software engineer at BMW Group's financial services business unit, building the digital checkout solution (DCS) product ecosystem. DCS is a configurable solution that enables BMW's suppliers and buyers interested in buying any of the BMW's branded (BMW, MINI, Motorrad, etc.) vehicles, parts or components in their respective markets. The product is currently deployed in more than 30 markets spanning across Asia, Europe and Australasia. Integrating with different dealers and payment processors through BMW payment services until I was promoted to **Solutions Architect**.

Entelect (ZA)

Senior Software Engineer

Jan. 2020 to May 2021

Senior software engineer consultant at Discovery S.A, at the group's information systems business unit on Discovery's financial advisor zone platform team.

Xpedia Applications (ZA)

Senior Software Engineer

Jul. 2019 to Dec. 2019

Worked on the custom software development department, a list of the client's systems worked on, including, but not limited to, SPSI's integrated country engine (ICE) platform.

ResRequest (ZA)

Worked in the software development department, part of the systems maintenance team, ensuring that ResRequest client's API connections to and from ResRequest servers are running.

Rocvest Group (ZA)

Software Engineer

Jul. 2014 to May. 2018

Worked as an offshoring consultant at various company projects, including Bottle's alcohol delivery app (rebranded to Pick n' Pay ASAP!; Health45 patient management platform; Beedhub delivery team, to mention a few, during his tenure there.

EDUCATION

Université de Montréal (Montréal, CA)

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD): Computer Engineering

Aug. 2024 (In-progress)

Dissertation: .

Stellenbosch University (Stellenbosch, ZA)

Master of Engineering (MEng): Industrial Engineering

Jan. 2022 to Jul. 2023 (Cum laude)

Thesis: An Evolutionary Algorithm for the Vehicle Routing Problem with Drones with Interceptions (VRPDi).

University of South Africa (Pretoria, ZA)

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A)

Jan. 2018 to Jul. 2019

Thesis: Exploring the Effects of Mergers and Acquisitions on Employee Job Satisfaction: A Case Study of Reservations Request Inc., KwaZulu-Natal.

Tshwane University of Technology (Pretoria, ZA)

Bachelor of Technology (BTech): Information Technology (Intelligent Systems)

Jan. 2012 to Jul. 2016

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Spoken Languages: Portuguese (Native), English (Excellent), French (Limited working proficiency)

Programming Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript/Typescript

Developer Tools: Jira, Git (Bitbucket, GitHub, GitLab), Docker, Postman, Insomnia, ELK, TIBCO, Redis, Swagger (OpenAPI)

Frameworks: Spring, Quarkus, JPA, Hibernate, Terraform, Angular2+, Node.JS, Django, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server, MongoDB

Cloud Technologies: AWS (EC2, S3, RDS, DynamoDB, Lambda, Elastic Cache, SQS, Athena, MSK, ECS, etc.), GCP (Compute Engine, BigQuery, etc.), Kafka

Soft Skills: Empathic leadership; Excellent communicator; Dependable; Critical thinker; Problem solver; Team worker;

Areas of Interest: Artificial intelligence (deep learning, machine learning, computer vision); Systems modelling; Programming; Politics and economics; Sports

Professional Memberships & Certificates

Institute of Information Technology Professionals South Africa (IITPSA)

Oct. 2017

Deep Learning by Deep Learning. AI on Coursera

Nov. 2023

DeepLearning.AI TensorFlow Developer by DeepLearning.AI on Coursera

Nov. 2023

REFERENCES

Available upon request.